Finding Aid for the Collection of Pamphlet Maps LSC.0990
UCLA Library Special Collections
- [Card files]
  - Collection of maps. London., v.d.; 7 maps. (Box 18)
    Plan of London; reduced ordnance map of London and environs; map of environs of London; reduced ordnance map of North Devon; environs of Cambridge.
    1. Gt. Brit. - Maps.
    2. London - Maps.
  - A new map of the county of Worcester divided into hundreds. London, printed for C. Smith, 1827; Col.map (Box 17)
    "corrected to 1827."
    1. Gt. Brit. - Maps
  - Colton's ... New York, J.H. Colton., 1865; Map. 167 x 199 cm.; Scale 1;1, 584,000. (Box 15)
    Colton's township and railroad map of the United States of america including a large portion of Canada, new Brunswick &c. showing the base, meridian and township lines of the U.S. surveys. Railroads and other internal improvements. Compiled from surveys in the U.S. Land Office and other authentic sources.
    Map does not include far western part of United States.
    2 insets: North America and Southern Florida.
    Decorative border with 16 pictorial views of cities of the United States.
    From the William Starke rosecrans papers with ms. annotations in his hand.
  - Sloane, Sir Hans, 1660-1753.
    See the following entry in this catalog: [Buache, Philippe] 1700-1773. Carte des terres aux environs du Japon... [1753]
  - Philips' new map of England and Wales. London, George Philip & son, [ca. 1900]; Col.map. (Box 17)
  - Regni Danici Insulae Seelandia, Fionia, Lalandia, Falstria, Langelandia, Mona..., ?*G 1025 S49 1948; col.map (Folder 37)
    Ex libris Warren c. Shearman.
    1. Denmark - Maps
    xSeutero, Matthaeo
  - Seller, John, 1667-1701.
    See the following entry in this catalog: Heermans, Augustus, 1621?-1686. Viginia and Maryland as it is planted ... 1941.
  - Stanford's map of central London., 1927; Col.map. index (Box 14)
    1. London - Maps.
    I. Standford, Edward, publ.
  - Stanford's map of Central London. London., 1906; Col.map. (Box 14)
    London - Maps.
    I. Stanford, Edward, publ.
  - Stanford's London atlas railway and station map of England and Wales and the hills and mountains carefully delineated and showing the distribution of urban population. London., 1886; Col.map. (Box 14)
    1. London - maps
  - Stanford's new map of the greater part of Europe extending from Moscow to the Atlantic and from the Gulf of Bothnia to the mediterranean. London, Stanford., 1900 (Box 14)
    Europe - Maps.
  - London with its postal sub-divisions... London, Edward Stanford, 1856; Col.map and street guide. (Box 14)
    Cover-title: Map of London, designed and engraved by the Society for the Diffusion of useful Knowledge, colored to show the new postal districts...
    1. London - Maps
  - Stanford, Edward, 1856-1917.
  - Stanford, Edward, 1827-1904.
  - Southern California maps: a miscellany of maps and guidebooks relating to Southern California since 1900. v.p., v.d.; 7 maps. (Box 32)
    1. Los Angeles - Maps.
    2. California, Southern - Maps.
  - Angol-Persian map of India, by J.B. Tassin. Calcutta, Oriental Lithographic Press., 1837; map 134 x 112cm fold to 31 1/2 x 24 1/2; Scale: 40 miles to the inch.; In portfolio.; Title lettering in English and Persian. (Box 9)
  - Tardieu, P.A.F.
    See: Tardieu, Antoine, François, 1757-1822.
  - Carte des routes de postes de l'empire français, du royaume d'Italie et de la confédération du Rhin. [Paris] P. Tardieu fils., 1814; 4 col.map sheets (Box 15)
    1. France - Maps.
    2. Europe - Maps.
    xTardieu, P.A.F.
  - The ancient cities of London & Westminster in the early part of the reign of Queen Elizabeth. London, J. Gardner & co., [1849]; panoramic map, 21 1/2 x 74 7/8 in., folded to 12 1/2 x 9 1/2 in.; Dedication signed: Nicholas Taperell and James Innes.; Cover-title: Plan of the ancient cities of London and Westminster. (Box 10)
    "this map ... was redrawn and published in the year 1849." -Brit.mus.Catalogue.
    I. Innes, James.
  - United States of America. 3d ed. Philadelphia, H.S. Tanner., 1832; Col.map; Insets of cities and areas. (Box 25)
    U.S. - Maps.
  - Stockdale, John, 1749[?] - 1814, publisher.
    See the following entry in this catalog: Map of the seat of war, in the northern part of Europe ... London, 1812.
    ?D 917 S86g
  - The counties of Perth and Clackmannan. London, Stobie, 1783; 2 map sheets. (col.) (Box 8)
  - Map of the city of Manila and vicinity. Manila, Office of Chief Engineer, division of the Philippines, 1901; Map. (Box 17)
    1. Philippine Islands - Maps.
  - Theatre of war, a mapof the country surrounding the Baltic sea, comprehending the northern part of Germany, Poland & Russia. London, C.Smith., 1812; Col.map. (Box 12)
    1. Europe - Maps.
    2. Baltic states - Maps.
  - Map of the United States, Canada, Mexico and the West Indies, with Central America, showing all the routes to California with a table of distances. New York, Thayer, Bridgman & Fanning., 1854; col.map (Box 31)
  - Taylor's maps of the environs of Dublin, extending 10 to 14 miles from the castle... Dublin, John Taylor., 1816; Map. (Box 10)
    1. Ireland - Maps.
  - ... New map of the county of Hereford. [London], 1754; Col.map. (Box 10)
  - ... Map of Hampshire, including the Isle of Wight. [London], 1759; 2 col.map sheets. (Box 10)
  - Dorset shire. [London], 1765; Col.map. (Box 10)
  - Map of Los Angeles compiled and drawn by Félix Violé. Los Angeles, Chamber of Commerce., 1904; Map. 67 x 53 cm.; No scale indicated.; Bordered with advertisements. (Box 32)
    [Removed for cataloging, 4/93] [JD??]
  - Vincenz
    See the following entry in this catalog: Progressive map service. Map of ... county, California, ca. 1916.
  - Velseri, Marci
    See: Welser, Marcus, 1558-1614.
  - Vandelli, Domenico, 1691-1754.
    See the following entry in this catalog: Bolzoni, Andrea.
  - Vance, D.H.
    See the following entry in this catalog: Finley, Anthony - Map of ...
  - U.S. Coast and Geodetic Survey
    See the following entry in this catalog: Nicholson, W.L., comp. Map of eastern Virginia ... 1864.
  - The state of Florida., 1846.; map. (Box 31)
    By J. Goldsborough Bruff; D. McClelland.
  - Chattanooga and its approaches, comp. in top.l engr. offic, hd. qrs. army Cumb. Topl. Engr. Office, Army of the Cumbd., 1864 (Box 17)
    From Rosecrans collection.
  - A township map of the state of Iowa. Fairfield, Iowa, Henn, Williams & co.; Philadelphia, R.L. Barnes., 1855.; col.map (Box 31)
    c1854 R.L. Barnes
    1. Iowa - Maps.
    I. Barnes, R.L.
  - Map of India from the most recent authorities. Drawn and engraved by I. and C. Walker. London, Wm. H. Allen & Co., 1863.; Col.map. 96 x 85cm.; Scale 1:4,100,000. (Box 15)
    Map shows railroads completed, in progress, and telegraph lines.
  - Map of India, from the most recent authorities. London, Wm. H. Allen & co., 1857.; Col.map (Box 15)
    "Drawn and engraved by T.&C. Walker"
    1. India - Maps
  - Map of India from the most recent authorities. Drawn and engraved by I.&C. Walker. London, Wm. H. Allen & co., 1849.; col.map. (Box 15)
  - Hampshire and Isle of Wight. London, Longman, Hurst, Rees, Orme & co., [ca.1870?]; Col.map. (Box 15)
    By J.&C. Walker
  - Walker, John, 1759-1830. DNB Walker, John, 1786/87-1873.
  - Walker, Charles
  - Waldseemüller, Martin, 1470-1521?
    See the following entry in this catalog: Minnesota, University. Library. James Ford Bell Collection. Antilia and America...
  - Environs de Paris. Revu et corrige par A. Vuillemin. [Paris] Maison Logerot, [ca.1870?]; Col.map. (Box 24)
    1. Paris - Maps.
  - Virginia. n.p., [ca.1847?]; col.map (Box 31)
    1. Virginia - maps.
  - [Sheet 17 of map of India] Surveyed by Major R. Shortrede, Captns. T.C. Glagrave, & M.G. Blythe. [London?], 1865 (Box 15)
    Engraved by J.&C. Walker.
  - Collection of illustrated guide-books. London, Ward, Lock and co., ca. 1912-1930.; 19 vols. illus. (Box 19)
    Bexhill; Bognor; Bournemouth (2); Budleigh Salterton; Buxton (2); Channel Islands (2); Eastbourne; Harrogate; Holland; Ilfracombe; Isle of Wight; London; Malvern; Nottingham; The Thames; Yarmouth.
    From Ogden collection guide-books.
    1. Voyages and travels
    2. Gt. Brit. - Maps.
  - Watson, Gaylord
    Watson's new rail-road and distance map ... 1871.
    Phelps & Watson's historical and military map of the border & southern states ... 1867.
  - Watson's new rail-road and distance map of the United States and Canada. New York, Gaylord Watson., 1871; col.map. (Box 31)
    2. Railroads - U.S. - Maps.
    I. Watson, Gaylord.
  - Weber's map of ... county, California. San Francisco and Los Angeles, C.F. Weber & co., 1914; 33 maps. (Box 29)
    Amador, Butte, Calaveras, Colusa, Contra Costa, Del Norte, Fresno, Glenn, Humboldt, Lassen, Merced, Modoc, Napa, Nevada, Plumas, San Francisco, San Benito, San Joaquin, San Mateo, Santa Clara, Santa Cruz, Shasta, Sierra, Solano, Sonoma, Stanislas, Sutter, Tehama, Tuolumne, Yolo, Yuba, Siskiyou, Santa Clara, rev. 1925 by Progressive Map Service.
    "Copyright 1914 Punnett brothers."
    I. Punnett brothers
    1. [Each county] - Maps.
    [Missing when coll. was prepared for moving from the Map Room to SRLF - se]
  - England and Wales. London, Cassell, Petter & Calpin, [1861?]; Col.map. (Box 12)
    Cover title: Cassell's map of England and Wales.
  - Islands of importance not delineated at large in the other maps of the atlas. London, Weller, [1861?]; Col.map. (Box 12)
    1. Islands of the Pacific - Maps.
  - Welser, Marcus, 1558-1614.
    See the following entry in this catalog: Peutinger table. Tabvla itineraria ex illustri Peutingerorum ...
  - Official transportation and city map of Los Angeles, Cal. and suburbs. Revised car routing showing car lines in official colors of operating companies, with complete route of each line. [Los Angeles], [ca.1920]; 1 map. 220 x 150 cm. (Box 31)
    [Removed for cataloging. 4/93.] [JD??]
  - A new map of the United States... showing also Canada and the Island of Cuba. Philadelphia, Lippincott, Grambo & co., 1853.; col.map. (Box 17)
    2. Cuba - Maps.
  - Guide maps to California wineries. San Francisco, Wine Advisory Board., 1951.; 1 v. (Box 22)
    1. California - Maps.
    2. Wine and wine making - California - Maps.
  - City map of Los Angeles. Wood's Red Book revised maps and vistors' guide. Los Angeles, Coast Card Co., 1922.; 1 map. With 24 p. guidebook attached. (Box 32)
    On verso of Los Angeles city map is map of Los Angeles and Vicinity. Inserted in pamphlet is a map of Los Angeles Harbor and Vicinity.
    [not here in '93]
  - Map of Prince Edward Island, in the Gulf of St. Lawrence ... with corrections and additions to 1874 by H.J. Cundall. [London? J & C Walker?], Col.map. (Box 13)
    Originally published in 1852.
    1. Canada - Maps.
  - Wyld, James, 1790-1836.
  - Map of Australia, compiled from the nautical surveys, made by order of the admiralty ... London, James, Wyld., ca. 1850.; Col.map. (Box 24)
    Inset: Van Diemens Land.
    1. Australia - Maps.
  - Map of the Burmese empire, constructed froma drawing compiled in the Surveyor General's Office, Calcutta, and other authentic documents. London., [ca.1800?]; Col.map. (Box 7)
    1. Burma - Maps.
    2. India - Maps.
  - ...Map of the routes through the Punjaub [sic] and the adjoining states. 2d ed. London, James Wyld., 1849.; Col.map. (Box 7)
    Second ed. superimposed on 1848 ed.
  - Map of India and Birmah. London, James Wyld., [ca.1860?]; Col.map. (Box 7)
  - Wyld's plan of London. London, James Wyld., 1881.; Col.map. (Box 7)
  - Young, James Hamilton
    [Finley, Anthony] Map of ...
    Mitchell, Samuel Augustus, 1792-1868.
    Mitchell's reference & distance map ... 1834.
  - Zannoni, Giovanni Antoni Rizzi
    See: Rizzi-Zannoni, Giovanni Antonio, 1736-1814.
  - Ziegler, jakob Melchior
    See: Ziegler-Steiner, jakob Melchior, 1801-1883.
  - The post office plan of London. London, Jas. Wyld., 1860.; Col.map. (Box 7)
  - Neue karte der Schwiez. Winterthur, J. Wurster, [1860?]; Col.map. (Box 13)
    xZiegler, Jakob melchior
    1. Switzerland - Maps.
  - Official automobile road map sectional and descriptive of California south of San Francisco. Los Angeles, M.P. Zindorf., 1905.; 1 v. (Box 32)